&gt;&gt; Okay, we are here in the Google Self-Driving Car.
‫حسنًا، نحن هنا بداخل سيارة Google ذاتية القيادة.
We're inside.
‫نحن بداخلها.
It's obviously driving itself.
‫وهي تقود نفسها كما نرى.
And it's doing everything by itself.
‫وتقوم بكل شيء بمفردها.
&gt;&gt; And I am here as a passenger.
‫&gt;&gt; وأنا هنا كراكب.
I'm really hoping that Sebastian did a good job in training this,
‫آمل حقًا أن يكون Sebastian قد درّب هذا الشيء جيدًا،
because he is not driving right now, and I-
‫لأنه لا يقود حاليًا، -
&gt;&gt; I am not driving, it drives better than me.
‫&gt;&gt; أنا لا أقود ولكن السيارة تقود بشكل أفضل مني.
&gt;&gt; I am at the mercy of this car.
‫&gt;&gt; أنا واقعة تحت رحمة هذه السيارة.
That's true, it does drive better than me.
‫هذا صحيح، إنها تقود بشكل أفضل مني.
&gt;&gt; So why are we talking about self-driving cars then?
‫&gt;&gt; إذن لماذا نتحدث عن السيارات ذاتية القيادة؟
&gt;&gt; Why are we talking about self driving cars?
‫&gt;&gt; لماذا نتحدث عن السيارات ذاتية القيادة؟
Well we're going to start by talking about supervised classification, and
‫لأننا سنبدأ في الحديث عن التصنيف الخاضع للإشراف،
self-driving cars are one big supervised classification problem.
‫وتعد السيارات ذاتية القيادة إحدى المسائل الكبرى المتعلقة بالتصنيف الخاضع للإشراف.
&gt;&gt; What does supervised mean?
‫&gt;&gt; ما الذي يعنيه "خاضع للإشراف"؟
&gt;&gt; Supervised means that you have a bunch of examples,
‫&gt;&gt; "خاضع للإشراف" تعني وجود مجموعة أمثلة.
where you know sort of the correct answer in those examples.
‫وأنت تعرف نوعًا ما الإجابة الصحيحة في هذه الأمثلة.
So I know that you have an example of this from the self-driving cars.
‫لذا فأنا أعرف أن لديك مثال على ذلك من السيارات ذاتية القيادة.
&gt;&gt; Yeah so I mean we train our car and
‫&gt;&gt; نعم، ما أعنيه هو أننا ندرب السيارة
we show the car what's the right behavior.
‫ونعرفها السلوك المناسب.
And we did the DARPA Grand Challenge we would take it out for a spin and it would
‫وقد خضنا تحدي Autobahn، فكنا نأخذ السيارة في جولة وكانت
very carefully watch us human drivers drive and would emulate our behavior.
‫تراقبنا نحن السائقين البشريين بدقة شديدة أثناء قيادتنا ثم تحاكي سلوكنا.
&gt;&gt; And in fact, this is sort of how people learn to drive, right?
‫&gt;&gt; وهذه في الواقع الطريقة التي يتعلم بها الناس القيادة، أليس كذلك؟
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I think so. When I was a child, I watched my parents drive.
‫&gt;&gt; نعم، أظن ذلك. فعندما كنت طفلاً، كنت أشاهد والديّ أثناء قيادتهم.
And they weren't really good drivers, but
‫ولم يكونوا ماهرين بالقيادة إلى حد كبير، ولكنني
I would still copy a lot of stuff from them.
‫مع ذلك كنت أقلد الكثير من أفعالهم.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, so it's kind of like,
‫&gt;&gt; نعم، فالبشر نوعًا ما يتعلمون
in the way the humans drive by watching lots of examples.
‫القيادة عن طريق مشاهدة العديد من الأمثلة.
That's what computers do when they're doing machine learnings.
‫وهو ما تقوم به أجهزة الكمبيوتر أثناء قيامها بعمليات التعلم الآلي.
You give them lots of examples, and they start to figure out what's going on.
‫فأنت تعطيهم الكثير من الأمثلة، ثم يبدؤون بدورهم في اكتشاف ما يحدث.
That's what we'll be learning about.
‫وهذا ما سنتعرف عليه.
&gt;&gt; And it's totally true.
‫&gt;&gt; وهو صحيح تمامًا.
In this unit, you're going to be learning about
‫في هذه الوحدة سنتعرف على
machine learning, the same way we program self-driving car.
‫التعلم الآلي، بالطريقة ذاتها التي قمنا بها ببرمجة الخطوات في السيارة.
You're going to program data and
‫ستقومون ببرمجة البيانات ثم
test out whether you can make a car go fast and slow at the appropriate time.
‫اختبار ما إذا كان بإمكانكم جعل السيارة تسرع أو تبطئ في الوقت المناسب.
using machine learning supervised learning.
‫وذلك باستخدام التعلم الآلي بطريقة التعلم الخاضع للإشراف.
&gt;&gt; That's right. So
‫&gt;&gt; هذا صحيح. إذن
we're going to be looking at a really cool terrain classification problem that
‫سنبحث مسألة رائعة حقًا خاصة بتصنيف التضاريس كانت
was very important for Stanley.
‫تمثل أهمية كبيرة بالنسبة لستانلي.
You want to introduce that?
‫فهل تريد تقديم ذلك؟
&gt;&gt; So, in Stanley's case, I was driving through the desert and
‫&gt;&gt; في حالة ستانلي، كنت أقود السيارة في الصحراء
the desert terrain is like ruts
‫وكانت الطرق الصحراوية مليئة بالأخاديد
and broom and can be very brutal.
‫والحواف الناتئة وهو ما يمكن أن يكون وعرًا للغاية.
So it you drive too fast, you are running the risk of flipping over and
‫لذا إذا كنت تقود بسرعة عالية، فأنت معرض لخطر الانقلاب
destroying yourself.
‫وتعريض نفسك للأذى.
So one thing we've trained the car to do is to really slow down at
‫لذا فإن أحد الأمور التي دربنا السيارة على القيام بها هي تقليل السرعة بالفعل
the appropriate time.
‫في الوقت المناسب.
We did this not by writing little rules,
‫ولم نقم بذلك عن طريق كتابة قواعد بسيطة،
we did it by us demonstrating to the car how we drive.
‫بل عن طريق توضيح طريقة قيادتنا للسيارة.
And it will just emulate us.
‫وهي فقط تقوم بمحاكاتنا.
&gt;&gt; How many miles did you have to drive to train that.
‫&gt;&gt; ما المسافة التي اضطررت إلى قطعها لتدريب السيارة؟
&gt;&gt; Oh thousands of miles.
‫&gt;&gt; أوه، الآلاف من الأميال.
We spent thousands of miles everyday in the desert.
‫قطعنا آلاف الأميال يوميًا في الصحراء.
&gt;&gt; Wow. &gt;&gt; And it took quite a while for it to become smart.
‫&gt;&gt; رائع. &gt;&gt; وتطلب الأمر مدة كي تصبح السيارة
&gt;&gt; Your poor grad students.
‫ذكية. &gt;&gt; يا لطلبة الدراسات العليا المساكين.
I can only imagine.
‫أستطيع تصور ذلك.
&gt;&gt; Well, I was the guy who had the pizza for everybody, but, it was a great time
‫&gt;&gt; حسنًا، لقد كنت الشخص الذي يحضر البيتزا للجميع، ولكن كانت تلك أوقات رائعة
because it was no email, we just had the, us and the software.
‫حيث لم يكن هناك بريد إلكتروني، كنا وحدنا مع البرامج.
And every time you got the software back it was very obvious,
‫وكل مرة كنا نستعيد فيها البرامج كان من الواضح أن
the car would punish us.
‫السيارة تعاقبنا.
&gt;&gt; Oh, that sounds great.
‫&gt;&gt; أوه، يبدو هذا رائعًا.
So, I think we should probably get started with that.
‫أظن أننا يجب أن نبدأ في ذلك
Let's try out a few different supervised classification problems.
‫لنجرب حل القليل من مسائل التصنيف الخاضع للإشراف المختلفة.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, so the unit's all about supervised learning, so let's dig in.
‫&gt;&gt; نعم، فموضوع هذه الوحدة بالكامل هو التعلم الخاضع للإشراف، إذن، لنتعمق في الموضوع.
&gt;&gt; Sounds great.
‫&gt;&gt; يبدو هذا رائعًا.